so the other day we were talking about
a nietzsche
and then you start talking about it in
terms of
uncertainty and
use that term what if
however as we were speaking is he said
we came as i said to you that's why
nibana is undetermined we will speak
about nibana i think is undetermined and you
nibana i think is undetermined and you
said
exactly uncertainty is the undetermined
and i was i thought that's not what i
meant actually
so if we could talk about that again
that undetermined you said
like uncertainty is the undetermined
when when it's purified of
ignorance well no just just you start
you start on a basic level just
colloquially speaking
if something is determined it implies
certainty uncertain things are less determined oh
uncertain things are less determined oh
it's not
so determined so it's uncertain well the
the the absolute pinnacle of the
the absolute pinnacle of the
undetermined thing
is uh
the phenomenon of nirvana the phenomenon
of
of complete asan kata dhamma as the
suttas would say
so what from the point of view of a mind
that depends on certainty that depends
on
nature and permanence and taking things
personally basically puttugena's mind
and ignorant mind nibana is the ultimate
uncertainty the most frightening thing
basically but uncertainty is frightening only
but uncertainty is frightening only
if you still take certainty for granted
and put it first
so if you think things are nature and
occasionally they're on each other
without realizing that a nietzsche
always that doesn't change
and your sense of nature is only
relative like slightly less than each
but still a nietzsche
so to speak so that's why that like
uncertainty is uh is the main characteristic of
is uh is the main characteristic of
nirvana but for somebody who has
developed nibana
that uncertainty is just the universal
nature of things
when the buddha did speak to lay people
or somebody who didn't have the right
view and they understood because you know
and they understood because you know
what what is it an ibana that you teach
what's the highest goal of your teaching
and he would describe what nibana is
and they would become distraught with
fear and
you know fall on the ground be the
breast pull their hair in anguish in his
eyes that but this reckless teaches will kill
that but this reckless teaches will kill
us
will destroy us so you train your mind
because if you train it the the uncertainty of
if you train it the the uncertainty of
nibana the dispassion of nibana
will be the utmost pleasure the highest
bliss but as the buddha said the neutral
but as the buddha said the neutral
feeling for example needs to be known
and understood
yeah if it's not known and not
understood it's going to be felt
extremely unpleasantly it's going to be
felt painfully
the neutral feeling so it requires
wisdom to be able to truly recognize what
to be able to truly recognize what
neutral feeling is and
find the peace in it takes wisdom for
peace not just on peaceful because the
not just on peaceful because the
peaceful feeling arose
that's not really the peace we're
talking about
so practically speaking if you even as a
non-arahant want to contemplate
the um well want to have a
theme for your contemplation they will
approximate the nibana
uncertainty the ultimate fundamental
uncertainty that's why mindfulness of
death one of the quickest ways
for for purifying mind of lust and
reaching ibana also the sharpest way
that can harm you
uh the other one when he said they would
have said that contemplation like it
will not be it will not be for me
he might not be and he won't be for me
um and that's like
when he said oh that's like the highest
contemplative view that would result in
serious amount of dispassion and
abandoning of the world
that even an outsider can't practice
somebody who hasn't understood the
dharma but the point being so what would be the
but the point being so what would be the
main characteristic of that view would
be the uncertainty
it will it might be it might not be
either way it won't be for me as in i
won't be taken as mine
like what is the what is the main
characteristic of mindfulness of death
that scares people a lot is the uncertainty
scares people a lot is the uncertainty
the
implicit every uncertainty of every like
you know
enduring experience that you have here
and now and when the buddha said how is
the mindfulness of death practice rightly it
mindfulness of death practice rightly it
was when the monk
described i practice it like after one
after an in-breath
i'm already practicing my friends that
before the next outbreak he says yeah
that's that's as close as it needs to
get that doesn't mean as i said before
that he's like focused so hard on every
he's like focused so hard on every
moment of
in breath death i'll draft that no it
just means that his context
is so firmly established on the
like a thorough sort of uncertainty
that underlies his entire existence that
he doesn't lapse
even for a moment of in or out breath
doesn't mean he goes
moment in breath moment death moment out
breath moment death
moment in breath moment death no means
the context is so strong
that even a little lapse does not occur
and why it is so strong because it is
true because it is factually uncertain on
because it is factually uncertain on
that level
for in breath you might not have an
outbreak
so it's not about like boiling down to a
moment to catch it it's more like just
sustaining the context
and recognizing the blatant truth of
your resistance
it's not about fabricating that's why i
say it needs to start
like only ibana is the highest bliss yes
eventually so how do you arrive at
bliss through a magical method and
technique by letting the truth take root in you
by letting the truth take root in you
know take over well by recognizing
basically the the
is again is the whole dhamma is the
universal characteristics of your
existence which are uncertainty
which are uncertainty
unsatisfactoriness the whole experience
is an experience of not self because
you cannot own that which is uncertain
because sense of ownership requires
sense of certainty
so that's already the form of
determination so uncertain means
undetermined or less determined
depending on how far you push the
uncertainty so if you want to contemplate a
so if you want to contemplate a
phenomenon that approximates nibana even
as a
contemplate uncertainty but contemplate
uncertainty as in
start feeling it contemplate yourself
within basically fully enclosed in a cage of
basically fully enclosed in a cage of
uncertainty
so there's no outside of that
uncertainty and everything that's inside
you don't really know
what's objected to from the outside so
you are fully inserted top to bottom
because what people would tend to do
same with the practice of anita is like
oh then you just start determining the
uncertainty over there
or determining on each over there in
other words you start determining what's
the undetermined which means it's not
really undetermined
so when people go around yes yes
everything is a nietzsche see this is an
each this is an each it's all a nature yeah
this is an each it's all a nature yeah
true factually theoretically but
practically that's not the nature that matters and
that's not the nature that matters and
each of the matters is deep
on the level of your existence and you
wouldn't be able to just say oh yeah
look my my eyes are a nature i can see that
my my eyes are a nature i can see that
my ears are on each and so on no because
you would feel that if you start feeling
your body
being under a threat of its existence
even if you say or not say these eyes
are on each of these ears of the nature
you're going to feel it
because it is factually a nature and
your life depends on it yet
it's uncertain so when you contemplate
uncertainty you will have to feel it that's why the
you will have to feel it that's why the
sealer needs to have been established
beforehand not acting out of greed aversion
not acting out of greed aversion
delusion because yeah some minds will
not be able to bear
the recognition of what nibana is as
they didn't when the buddha told them
like if the mind is strong enough it
will not get distraught
in the face of anxiety towards
uncertainty he would be like wow
i better do something about it like that
king when the buddha told him like the
four mountains coming from every
direction about to crush you what are
you going to do
he said well first there's this mountain
from the easter salad on west there's
mountain from the west iran no there's
mud from the north around south mount
from the south
or well in that case i will quickly
denounce this life and you know like
well there are four mountains coming so
do what you see fit he didn't lose his
mind obviously
but some people got overwhelmed by that
everybody can
feel that uncertainty and
it's i for petunia for someone who's not
trained it would be anxiety sure and then
it would be anxiety sure and then
that anxiety can proliferate into all
sorts of phobias or whatever
exactly fears yeah all kinds you know
but once if you can handle and see that
anxiety or that uncertainty in certainly yeah
or that uncertainty in certainly yeah
and you
endure that uncertainty because if
you're able
and again you will be able if you
actually made the effort to practice
sensory straightening beforehand
the reason people become mad is because
people perform
mad actions they do mad stuff they say
man stuff
you cannot be mad if you don't act out
manly
you're not mad then it doesn't matter
what goes through your head if you don't
act out on your thoughts
you're not mad madness becomes when you
act out every single time
so if you have practice restraint you
will be able to not act out and the
reason why this is necessary is because
anxiety is not uncertainty and certainly
is not anxiety
but for an untrained mind and the
uncertainty is anxious
but for the trained mind they go used to
uncertainty and recognize it and
started understanding it practicing its
way towards the ibana and complete
cooling down on a kind of uncertainty
because by the way that's how this
passion happens when the mind realizes
this is not
worth clinging to this is not worth
owning or acting out or possessing or
indulging it
it's unworthy of that effort because
it's so
thoroughly uncertain so the mind that
does start practicing like that with
uncertainty you get used to it
means you will not feel anxiety towards
it so the anxiety
aspect of uncertainty was due to your
ignorance in regard to uncertainty not
because of uncertainty
and as you won't be becoming
dispassionate if you don't actually sit with that
if you don't actually sit with that
well yeah this passion this passion is a
result of you basically seeing things right
of you basically seeing things right
it's not something you can just choose
to do
i choose to be this passionate i choose
to do another yeah i choose to be an
author or something like that
dispassion relinquishing of ownership
will be the result of recognizing that
that which you are passionate towards and
which you are passionate towards and
owning and so on your existence your
sense basis
your whole body your whole life is not
worth clinging to
it's not worth owning yeah but once you
don't then
oh it's not worth earning i'll let me
not own it yeah
yeah it will be automate it will be
that's when it will be a result like
like you have a headache due to some
bacterial infection
you take antibiotics you get rid of the
bacteria headache disappears
you don't need to go and take a headache
pill now because the headache was the
symptom of the infection
the high fever or whatever it was
so going back a bit when you're talking
about neutral feeling
uh-huh feeling which is neither
pleasant or unpleasant so it's in a way
you can use that word undetermined it's
undetermined well
already it's less determined it's less
difficult it's certainly not determined
as agreeable
well it's you can say it's determined as
neither determined as agreeable no
determinism unagreeable disagreeable so why
unagreeable disagreeable so why
why is this important right
well there are only three types of
feelings for in nibana for an arahant
whoever has purified his experience
anagami is not like a new feeling that he has on
is not like a new feeling that he has on
top of these three
so the existence is the five aggregates
the difference is the level of passion
and delight in the fire aggregate or
freedom from those things from the five
aggregates so it's important because you start as a
so it's important because you start as a
pathogen that
always starts basically on the level of
full infatuation
full ownership full passion full
dependence on pleasure
full avoidance of pain full ignorance of
neither pleasure nor pain
and you see that just like boredom is
always like the practical example
so it's not pleasant or unpleasant but
it's really unpleasant because there is
nothing happening there's nothing felt
more determinately so to speak
and yeah like even you can see that even
with people who become heavily dependent
on sensuality
just slight uh reduction
in the level of feeling that they have
on a kind of sensuality
will feel like oh pain it's still the
pleasure but not enough pleasure it
becomes extreme pain
because you become so much more
dependent now on even more determined
feeling and more determining feeling
and more determined feeling and that
determination is
comes directly from away from ignorance
from ignoring the certain truths
the certain nature of what's right in
front of you
it's on the metaphysical relationship
between the two
not knowing the nature of the feeling
not not not understanding
that it's not worth the lighting to
you're automatically determining it as
more and more
delightful like escape from pain becomes
more delightful than the actual pain
and again people who become so soft
mentally so touchy so so so sort of uh weak
so touchy so so so sort of uh weak
um they would then find pain
just in the in the lack of pleasure and
they will try to have to get rid of it
so that's like the people's like
everything is comfortable but then these
tiny little things and they can't let go
of the minds cannot let go of the tiny
little imperfections so to speak and if that
imperfections so to speak and if that
experience starts to revolve around the
pain and kind of getting rid of that one
and kind of getting rid of that one
imperfection ignoring the reality
of their experience as a whole which is
far more pleasant already because that's
what they've been cultivating
that's what they've been determining
repeatedly looking for faults looking
for pain
fearing the pain then obviously because
you start seeing it more and more
that's like a dog who tried to out tries
to outrun the post
that it's tied to and ends up being
completely like
revolving around it until the the chain
is so tight now it cannot move now all
you see
is just pain here and pain there and
trouble here and anxiety there and over
there but first thing you have to do is not
but first thing you have to do is not
act out of it start practicing sense
restraint that will enable you to you still have
that will enable you to you still have
to endure it endurance of
of feelings is not optional the only
difference the only thing that is optional is how
the only thing that is optional is how
you're going to go about it
if you're trying to get rid of the
feeling your whole life is about finding
pleasure avoiding pain
and distracting yourself you do that
fully on the basis of having to endure
these things when they're felt
otherwise you wouldn't feel them if you
choose to practice sense restraint and
endure it on those terms
you still have to endure it but there is
a benefit of that because you can
actually sense restraint first can result in
sense restraint first can result in
wisdom and that's what buddha said
you replace the pains of a household the
life household in mind
with the pains of an enunciate life the
enunciated mind you replace them
it's not optional pain is not optional
feeling is not optional
so then you have you replace the
household as joys and happiness
with the happiness of renunciation
either way feeling will have to be there
you are subjected to it you will have to
endure it
so then it's just how you go about it so
the neutral feeling
is that recognition that comes out of
wisdom that the neutral feeling is by
far the best because pleasure pressures you
the best because pleasure pressures you
towards more pleasure
pain obviously pressures you towards
getting rid of it dealing with it
quickly addressing it manage it get rid
of it
neutral feeling you realize oh it's
undetermined i'm undetermined in the neutral feeling
i'm undetermined in the neutral feeling
i'm not pressured
but then it's your ignorance of the
neutral feeling that then pressures you
towards distraction and delusion as the
buddha would say
so when not known neutral feeling you're
going to be unpleasant about it
when known oh you're going to be very
pleasant about it
so to know knowing neutral feeling
if you want to know the neutral feeling
you have to start restraining the the
delight and pleasure
and you have to stop trying to get rid
of the pain
by default because neutral feeling is is
a
result of restraint
it's kind of well no neutral feeling is
on the level of three feelings
but you understanding the neutral
feeling will be the result
of restraint and seeing through the
nature of the other two feelings that
are more obvious
but neutral feeling was there anyway you
realize many times in the past even as a
complete future
you had neutral feelings but you never
understood the value of it
because for that you needed the sense
restraint in regard to positive
feeling and the negative feeling
developed beforehand thoroughly
and then starting the nature of it
through that endurance
so you see the value in neutral yeah you
see the value in
uncertainty you see the value in in in
neither positive nor negative
you see the value in non-disturbance
you see the value in this passion you
see the value in
in disenchantment because you know most
people don't see the value in this
passion my passion is good provides me with
my passion is good provides me with
pleasure ambition drive for life
and from that point of view yeah that's
the household of joy
but in order to have that joy means you
also have to be
blind to the implicit danger of that
same very thing that you're passionate
about and because if you do become aware of
and because if you do become aware of
the danger as the way they would say
you discern that the danger that's
apparent then you realize oh it's not
worth clinging to
so then it's not a choice really oh i
choose them to stop clinging to this or
something no no automatically you realize oh it's
no no automatically you realize oh it's
a trap and no trap is worth being
trapped by
so only time you get trapped by a trap
is when you don't see it as a trap
so contemplate uncertainty as being
is you being within it not as an object
of your attention
but as a background of your experience
as a whole
start seeing the characteristics of uncertainty
uncertainty
and you develop that done act out of it
sustain your restraint in your sealer
you will
force your mind to become dispassionate
to become disenchanted and that's when
the mind starts seeing clearly when the
cloud of the dust of passion disappears that's it
so all determinations are
uncertain so what is that
then how will then that
make those things that are determined by
those determination b
so if determinations are uncertain what
is then to be said about things that are
being determined by those determinations
they are even more uncertain [Music]
all determinations are uncertain and all
determinations are unsatisfactory thus
are unsatisfactory thus
everything that's determined
cannot be owned
determinations what do you mean by
determinations well practically speaking determinations
well practically speaking determinations
you know you can get very technical
about it and you know you should
certainly familiarize yourself with the meaning of
familiarize yourself with the meaning of
that word definitely
and the in parliament itself just just
get different ideas and broaden your
different ideas and broaden your
understanding just of the terms so that
you can then know what to recognize in
your experience but
practically speaking in very plain terms
determination would be
anything that is a basis for your
ownership practically speaking
so say i'm very attached to my house
my my family my car and so on so you can
now take that the joy that you get on
take that the joy that you get on
account of it
is determined by having the house by
having the car by having the family
but then when you look at that you can
take even further so determinations are
not a fixed thing it's more like a
determining a relationship based on how
you feel
whether you feel ignorant infatuated
avoiding pleasure
avoiding pain pursuing pleasure that's
going to be on the basis of something
that basis is what determines your
experience as such
so understanding determination frees you
from these wrong things that your mind
cultivates that's why cessation
determination is nibana and um so you could then say
is nibana and um so you could then say
um like you you're attached to your
whatever so your family presence of their bodies
so your family presence of their bodies
presence of your body presence of your
senses presence of their senses
literally eyes and random organs is now
the basis
for this entire emotional relationships
the relationship that you have with your
family and your dependence and your
ownership and fear if they have threat
and joy if they're successful and so on
but that would be inconceivable if your
body would not be there
if you would die so the fundamental one
of the fundamental
determinations obviously it's the having
the body functioning body
so your body is one the the fundamental
determination that's why like
mindfulness of the body
done properly maintaining the context of
the body is the basis for
any experience in your life we already
with the recognition of the uncertainty
of that determination of that context
makes then whatever you experience on
the basis of that context of your body
unhonorable so your own children
family everything it's still there it's
still perceived yet now
the emotional basis for your ownership
is gone everywhere
because it's seen on the basis of
uncertainty yeah
all your life missions your life
everything
bit more obvious because actually people
think i think you can just be mindful of
the body
takes a lot of wisdom to develop this
level of clarity of the context of the
body as a determination for everything
you wouldn't see a connection basically
what i'm saying most people would not
see a connection between
present enduring body as such and their
dependence on the emotional joy that
they get on account of their daughter
getting a degree in a university or
something they wouldn't see that but it this is
they wouldn't see that but it this is
the fundamental
fundamental um determination
that is when you see that determination
as being a nature
well when you see that your own body
that you're not in control of is
perpetual the main characteristic of it
is the uncertainty
then what doesn't matter what comes your
way like you would need to pretend that
your daughter didn't get the best degree
at her university but you will be unable
to forget
the the container the the utmost
fundamental background of that
experience which is
uncertainty in other words it will have
to come in
you wouldn't be able to get involved
well you the like
you can again as as many times you know
in the suttas like
western laymen or even like monks are
hands you know you still talk discuss
you know you still talk discuss
help give advice on mundane matters it's
not like you stop to recognize the
significance of it
but what a parent who has suddenly
become anagami or narand hears that the
anagami or narand hears that the
daughter is the best at university
what they will be unable to do is take
the ownership of that experience as a
whole so they will be unable to lose the sight
so they will be unable to lose the sight
of the uncertainty
so they will probably you know just help
the daughter
rejoice in mundane matters so to speak
but fundamentally be completely
unmoved that's what when they would
exclaim in the sutta and yet my
composure remained unchanged
whether it was extremely positive
experience and negative the composure of
the mind remained unchanged
oh yeah my only son was being falsely
accused and killed
but my composure remained unchanged
isn't this dumb wonderful
well the mind established upon the
undetermined upon the uncertain as the
fundamental like non-negotiable basis the truth the
like non-negotiable basis the truth the
reality of things the nibana
then it's inconceivable to resist the
uncertainty is because resisting the uncertainty is
is because resisting the uncertainty is
uncertain
but you need to hammer that through that
emotional barrier
that your ownership towards things is
and when the buddha did describe to some
people what what determinations are he
actually did
he referred to exactly this uh the
possessions the the king was determined by his
the the king was determined by his
king's possessions
those were his determinations of his
you know statute of stature of a king
he's his rulership he's obviously
self-perception his joy that comes on
with all the perks and benefits of a king he
all the perks and benefits of a king he
says would he be a king
if he didn't have a kingdom if he didn't
have the castle if he didn't have the
horses if he didn't have the army
if he wouldn't be the king my sense of
self well that's exactly
you realize so your sense of self needs
to have these determinations
that you blindly own by not
understanding their uncertainty
so the point to consider here in this
case it's not like
oh so you just go around throwing things
away and say i don't own this i don't
own this i don't know this
all you need to do is find things that
because you can't throw away your body
like that
you can't just say okay i throw away my
senses and i'm another hand it doesn't
work like that
so all you need to do is find what you
do on and through that ownership
start discerning the uncertainty of that
thing and that's going to be felt
anxiously at least initially
if the mind is developed you will not
suffer much of an account of anxiety
but it's still the same route you have
to go that's when the buddha describes
sometimes is it a pleasant way towards out of
is it a pleasant way towards out of
handship quick and pleasant
slow and pleasant quick and painful slow
and painful
it's the same way it's just how slow
you're gonna go and how much you're
gonna suffer on account of it or not
but it's the same way through the sense
of ownership discerning the uncertainty
the mind that has developed somebody
will not be moved by that uncertainty
will not feel as much anxiety the mind
that hasn't
will feel a lot of it or relatively
speaking depending on how much you
develop so samadhi as i said before is not
so samadhi as i said before is not
measured by how
peaceful and blissful you had your
meditation session until the bell rang
it's imagine how much you don't move in
the face of uncertainty
in the face of sensuality in the face of
pain in the place of
threat misfortune how much is your mind
like scraping for the walls to outrun
the pain or how much is it like the
mountain that would describe it doesn't
move whether it's the wind
rain hailstorm or whatever else
that is what samad is and that's why
exactly the the beginning of the right
samadhi the first jana starts through
fully surmounting not being moved by the
five hindrances
or the will say by the joys and griefs
in regard to the world
you develop that samadhi of jannah not
i watch my nostril i enter jana and then
i don't get the hindrances and joy of
the world which is what people hope for
no no you work through that
then the result is samadhi then the
result is the pleasure of that seclusion
and safety and relief
and that's what jhana is so samadhi is
the measure of immovability
in the face of any pressure positive or
negative but usually negative
and fundamental yeah that was exactly
the reaction of people when they heard
nibana as the fundamental uncertainty
uncertainty they had no samadhi they had no they had
they had no samadhi they had no they had
no sila
they had no samadhi so they were
completely overwhelmed when they
understood what the buddha was saying
what his teaching is or they will kill
me that will destroy me that is the true
death of me
because from patricia's point of view it
is yeah and that's why
samadhi you you practice healer you
practice sensory strain you invest the
effort you grind you endure
that is the samadhi already not now i
watch my nostrils together samadhi and
peaceful experience no
you already have somebody to the extent
you're able to not break your precepts
because to that extent you're able to
endure the negative pressure
the pull of centrality is going to and
the more you
uh make things clearer the more pressure
you're going to see that's it
is there you can see that the pressure
becomes even clearer it becomes even
clearer so
i said it the other day that i start
meditation and as if i'm doing it right i'm
and as if i'm doing it right i'm
supposed to have pleasant feelings
yeah yes exactly exactly yeah but it's
actually the opposite
it's completely opposite samadhi is the
work that basically is born out
that basically is born out
of your work of your sealer work of your
sense restraint
not just do i keep the precepts i don't
think about him do i also practice sense
restraint in between
keeping the precepts do i just let my
eyes see whatever they want ears chase
the sounds body chase the touches
or do actually impose sense restraint on
that so sila samadhi is the result of it and
so sila samadhi is the result of it and
then that's then you see oh so you
develop samadhi
now by watching your nostrils by by
fortifying that with your seal a creator
for you
and what's the result then silva samadhi
ah
clear seeing understanding through what
you have cultivated
but more often than not okay silas over
there yeah i'm a good person
let me give me the technique let me
watch and also let me have special
blissful experience when my body
trembles with joy and so on and then the
experience of that must be some sort of
wisdom in in jhana in my panya
and thus that's my practice completely
upside down
you're just chasing another agreeable
pleasure you damage your samadhi by ability to
you damage your samadhi by ability to
withstand pain
mentally you measure it basically by you
know how deeply you were away when you were
how deeply you were away when you were
sleeping or meditating
it's fine if you get blissful
experiences but don't measure your
samadhi by that
quite the opposite take them with a
pinch of salt
and as a samadhi is when my mind is
throughout the day
not moved by joys and griefs in regard
to the world and what is the world
literally everything side sound smell taste
everything side sound smell taste
touches
is the world for your mind and your mind
is not moved by anything that's what
samadhi is
not i had such a powerful samadhi i was
unaware of the world for three hours
which is the same when i go to sleep and
and and that's my samadhi no
that's just probably being asleep or
switched off
for whatever reason
abandoning the joys and griefs in regard
to the world and
basically cultivating the context of
uncertainty will force you will compose your mind
will force you will compose your mind
force your mind into samadhi
is another way for saying samadhi
that which is loose and scattered so
there's going to be
some effort involved there
rounding up exactly effort of striving
to rounding up the precepts the sensory
strength tighter tighter tiger and you have
tighter tighter tiger and you have
composed now what you need to see
so you want to do meditation session
sit down and then see
bring up the joys and griefs of the
world and see how much your mind moves
bring up the liability as we often say
well i'm fine now i'm not grieving over
anything could i
what if my next phone call is bad news
will i be distraught do i know for sure
that as
the anagam is in the status exclaim
isn't it wonderful my composure remain
unchanged can i say that
do i know for sure my composure will
remain unchanged regardless of
the news that comes is my only son is
being falsely imprisoned and just
murdered and my composure remains unchanged not
and my composure remains unchanged not
because i didn't hear the news rightly
but i don't know significance of my only
son otherwise she wouldn't have said my
only son
she didn't engage in oh he's just matter
he's just elements he's just a nature
no my only son that i've bred
raised protected a good person
falsely imprisoned by the king falsely
accused falsely tried and executed
so fully aware of the significance of
this extreme
personally personal injustice
and the mind remained unchanged isn't it
like by composure it may not change so
by composure it may not change so
is that somebody do you know that am i
liable to things changing my composure if so
to things changing my composure if so
that's your work
so on the reason last on other reason
hindrances can they arise and beset my mind and
can they arise and beset my mind and
overwhelm it and make me
run for the walls or have i developed my
mind to be
unmoved because if you're unmoved that's
when you get to see things clearly
not while you're running and shaking
first you need to stop moving
stop trying to stop overly indulging in
things moving towards them stop trying
to
run them moving away from them and stop
turning a blind eye
and ignoring them